Esta é a lição 12 de Pimsleur Inglês 1.
Listen to this telephone conversation. Escute esta conversa de telefone.
Listen to this telephone conversation. Peter está
falando com sua amiga Mary. Hello,
Mary. It's Peter. How are you? Hello, Peter.
I'm fine, thanks. And you? I'm fine too.
Mary, would you like to have dinner with me tonight at the Park Avenue Restaurant?
Not tonight, Peter, but tomorrow night I'd like to.
At what time? At 7 o'clock? Okay,
tomorrow night at 7 o'clock at the Park Avenue Restaurant. And thank you.
You're welcome. Goodbye, Mary. Goodbye,
Peter. Listen again. Listen again.
Hello, Mary, it's Peter. How are you? Hello, Peter.
I'm fine, thanks. And you? I'm fine too. Mary,
would you like to have dinner with me tonight at the Park Avenue Restaurant?
Not tonight, Peter, but tomorrow night I'd like to. At what time?
At seven o'clock. Okay, tomorrow night at seven o'clock
at the Park Avenue Restaurant, and thank you. You're welcome.
Goodbye, Mary. Goodbye, Peter. Você se lembra de
como se diz hoje à noite?
Tonight. Tonight.
今天晚上。Tomorrow night.
Tomorrow. Tomorrow night.
今天晚上。 At six o'clock.
At six o'clock.
Tente perguntar, não mais tarde?
Not later?
Not later? Diga então
às sete.
Then at seven o'clock.
Seven.
Then, then at seven o'clock.
或是八点。Or at eight o'clock.
Pergunte que horas são agora.
What time is it now?
Pergunte se ele sabe que horas são.
Do you know what time it is?
Diga-lhe que são dez horas agora.
It's ten o'clock now.
It's ten o'clock.
Diga não, são quatro.
No, it's four o'clock.
It's four o'clock. Pergunte outra vez que horas são agora.
What time is it now?
Diga, são cinco horas.
It's five o'clock.
Diga eu vou comer às cinco.
I'm going
to eat at five o'clock.
Sem mudar a ordem das palavras, pergunte você vai comer?
You're going to eat?
Com quem? With whom?
Diga com você.
With you. Eu vou comer
com você.
I'm going to eat with you.
Diga sim, eu também gostaria de comer.
Yes, I'd like to eat too.
Eu gostaria de jantar com você.
I'd like to have dinner with you.
Eu gostaria de jantar com você hoje à noite.
I'd like to have dinner with you tonight.
At the hotel.
Ele responde: Tudo bem. Listen and repeat.
All right.
Right. Right.
All. All right.
All right.
Em inglês, esta resposta é mais formal do que ok. Diga tudo
bem. Preste atenção na pronúncia.
All right. Right.
All. All right.
Você vai tomar um pouco de vinho? Listen and repeat.
Are you going to have some wine?
To have.
To have some wine.
Diga outra vez. Você vai tomar um pouco de vinho?
Are you going to have some wine?
Diga não. Eu vou tomar uma cerveja.
No, I'm going to have a beer.
Diga hoje.
Today. Today.
Você se lembra de como se diz eu não sou americano?
I'm not American.
I'm not. Agora tente dizer da mesma maneira: eu não vou jantar
I'm not going to have dinner today.
Sem mudar a ordem das palavras, pergunte: Você não vai jantar?
You're not going to have dinner?
Responda: Não, hoje não.
No, not today.
Eu não vou jantar hoje.
I'm not going to have dinner today.
Diga: hoje eu vou comer às quatro.
Today, I'm going to eat at
four o'clock. Today, I'm going to eat at four o'clock.
Chiga, o às três.
Or at three o'clock.
E eu vou tomar um pouco de vinho.
And I'm going to have some wine.
Diga, tudo bem, então às três.
All right, then at three o'clock.
É assim que se pergunta quanto algo
custa. Listen and repeat. How much is it?
Much. Much.
How much?
How much is it?
Pergunte outra vez. Quanto custa? Literalmente,
quanto é?
How much is it?
É assim que se diz um dólar. Listen and repeat.
One dollar.
Dollar.
Lur.
Doll, dollar.
One, one dollar.
Quanto custa?
How much is it?
Diga um dólar.
One dollar.
One dollar, sir.
Você não ouviu bem o que ela disse. Pergunte concisamente: Quanto?
How much? Tente dizer
oito dólares.
Eight dollars.
Dólares. Diga tudo bem.
All right. All right.
Agora é assim que se diz onze dólares.
Listen and repeat. Eleven dollars.
Eleven.
V, fun.
Eleven, eleven,
eleven dollars.
Diga onze dólares.
Eleven dollars.
Pergunte: Quanto custa?
How much is it?
How much? É assim
que se diz: Doze dólares. Listen and repeat.
Twelve dollars.
Twelve. V.
Twelve.
Diga doze dólares.
Twelve dollars.
Pergunte quanto?
How much?
Diga dois dólares.
Two dollars.
Doze dólares.
Twelve dollars.
Onze dólares.
Eleven dollars.
Eleven. Um dólar.
One dollar.
One.
One. One dollar.
Agora é assim que se diz treze dólares. Listen and
repeat. Thirteen dollars.
Teen. Teen,
thir, thirteen,
thirteen,
thirteen dollars.
Diga treze dólares.
Thirteen dollars.
Pergunte quanto custa.
How much is it?
Tente responder: custa doze dólares. Use a
It's twelve dollars.
It's. It's twelve dollars. Custa treze dólares.
It's thirteen dollars.
Onze dólares.
Eleven dollars.
Ten dollars.
Oito dólares.
Eight dollars.
Doze dólares.
Twelve dollars.
Two dollars.
Nine dollars.
Six dollars.
Pergunte: Quanto custa?
How much is it?
Diga: Custa $7. It's $7.
Diga:
Eu não entendo.
I don't understand.
Tente perguntar: Custa cinco dólares?
Is it five dollars?
Pergunte-me se eu quero cinco dólares.
Do you want five dollars?
Do you want?
Custa cinco dólares.
Is it five dollars?
Diga não, custa quatro dólares.
No, it's four dollars.
No, ma'am, it's four dollars.
E sete dólares.
And seven dollars.
Chica custa treze dólares.
It's thirteen dollars.
Chica não, treze dólares não.
No, not thirteen dollars.
Pergunte: custa 12 dólares?
Is it twelve dollars?
Diga não, 11 dólares.
No, eleven dollars.
Você não ouviu bem o que ele disse. Diga, por favor,
repita.
Please repeat.
Repeat, please.
I'm sorry. Please repeat.
E como ele diz, por favor, escute.
Please listen.
Listen, please.
Pergunte: Você entende?
Do you understand?
Diga: Sim, agora eu entendo.
Yes, now I understand.
Você se lembra de como se diz um dólar?
One dollar.
One. One dollar.
Custa um dólar.
It's one dollar. Então custa um dólar.
Then it's one dollar.
Diga tudo bem? All right.
Now listen. O que eu te disse? Eu disse escute agora.
Você vai falar com um homem. Escute e responda.
Listen and answer. Escute e responda.
Hello, how are you today?
Fine, thanks.
I'm fine,
thank you.
You speak English very well. Diga que não, não muito
No, not very well.
Not very well.
I don't speak English very well.
I don't speak English very well. Agora,
o homem vai propor diversas coisas que vocês podem fazer juntos.
Não concorde nenhuma vez. Se ele quiser cerveja,
você vai querer vinho. Se ele quiser fazer algo hoje,
você vai querer fazê-lo amanhã. Se ele quiser fazê-lo às seis,
você vai preferir fazê-lo às sete. Agora escute e
responda. Listen and answer. Would you like something to
eat?
No, I'd like something to drink.
No thanks.
No thank you.
Would you like some wine?
No, I'd like a beer.
A beer, please.
Okay, when? Today?
No, not today. Tomorrow?
Tonight?
No, not tonight. Tomorrow night.
At what time? At 5 o'clock?
No, not at 5 o'clock. At 6 o'clock.
Not at 6. At 7 o'clock?
No, not at 7 o'clock. At 8 o'clock?
No, at 10 o'clock, please.
Not at ten o'clock, at eleven o'clock.
All right. Tomorrow night at eleven o'clock. Goodbye.
Agora você vai conversar com uma moça. Ela é vendedora numa loja.
Você compra algo e não está de acordo com o preço que ela propõe.
Oponha-se a cada preço que ela te dá. Sugerindo pagar um dólar a
menos em cada preço proposto. Comece perguntando à vendedora
quanto as suas compras custam.
How much is it?
Excuse me, how much is it?
It's thirteen dollars.
No, not $13. It's $12.
No, sir. It's $11. It's $11.
No, not $11. It's $10.
It's $10.
No, not $10. It's $9.
No, not $9. It's $8.
All right then, eight dollars. Você lhe dá oito dólares.
Escute e responda ao que ela te diz. Thank you, sir.
You're welcome.
You're welcome, miss.
Nesta lição de inglês um se incluem exercícios de leitura.